A Guide to the Papers of Stuart Brown and Tilghman Bunch 1860-1970
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Stuart Brown and Tilghman Bunch, 1860-1970
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6528-c, -d
This collection consists of ca. 500 items (4 Hollinger boxes and 1 oversize folder).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Both groups of papers were gien to the Library by Stuart E. Brown, Jr. of Berryville, Virginia, on June 4, 1990.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of Stuart E. Brown, Jr. (1916- ), Berryville, Virginia, and Tilghman Howard Bunch, Washington, D.C. include photographs, correspondence, political papers, postcards, accounts, itineraries, memorabilia, newsclippings, voting lists, printed materials, and bible records and genealogy.
The papers of Stuart Brown contain political records concerning his work with the Clarke County Democratic Committee, including several types of voter lists, Brown's candidacy for the Virginia House of Delegates in 1961, and the possibility of Brown running in the 1965 Special Election to fill the Virginia State Senate seat left vacate by Harry F. Byrd, Jr. Also present are special files on J. Kenneth Robinson, Stuart E. Brown, Jr., and William Spong.
The papers of Tilghman Howard Bunch form the bulk of the collection. These chiefly consist of the correspondence of Bunch; memorabilia associated with his career in the Navy; itineraries for his numerous voyages and trips; and photographs of the Bunch family, the Lewis and related families, trips taken by Bunch abroad, the U.S.S. Mayflower, and miscellaneous persons and places.
Letters from Bunch to his mother, Laura Crease Lewis Bunch, and other relatives, were written while serving in the Navy, [1925 ?]-1926, aboard the U.S.S. Scorpion and describe his experiences at various ports of call. Bunch had recently transferred from a destroyer to the yacht U.S.S. Scorpion, which was used by Admiral Bristol, the U.S. High Commissioner to Turkey. Bunch visited Gibralter; Alexandria, Cairo, and Luxor, Egypt; Beirut, Syria; Venice, Italy; Phaleron Bay, Delphi, Thebes, the Bay of Nauplia, Mt. Athos, and Salonica, Greece; Constantinople, Turkey; the Black Sea; and Constanza and Bucharest, Romania.
Bunch comments concerning his opinion of Greek immigrants (1926 June 9); the Greek leader Theodorus Pangalos (1878-1952) (1926 June 18); and changes in the complexion of Salonica from a Turkish to a Greek city (1926 July 1). A friend in Spain writes concerning the fall of France in World War II (1941 March 18) and the assassination of John F. Kennedy (1963 November 25).
Contents List
- Stuart Brown, Jr. Papers 1960-1971
  - Clark County Democratic Committee 1962-1971, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Club Lists 1960, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Printed Material and Newsclippings re: Stuart E. Brown, Jr. 1961 (Box 1)
  - Robinson, J. Kenneth: State Senate 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Spong, William: General Election 1966 (Box 1)
  - Teacher's List 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Voting Lists: Clarke County 1961 (Box 1)
  - Voting Lists: Frederick County 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Voting Lists: Winchester 1960-1961, n.d., 3 folders (Box 2)
- Papers of Tilghman H. Bunch 1911-1970
  - Bible Records and Genealogical Material 1911-1962, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence [1925?]- 1970, n.d., 5 folders (Box 2)
  - "Diary" of Margaret Lewis Typescript, 1730-1775 n.d., 19 pages (Box 2)
  - Estate of Mattie L. Warwick 1929 (Box 2)
  - Itineraries 1950-1966, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Memorabilia re: the Career of Tilghman H. Bunch 1922-1929 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Papers 1860-1970, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Newsclippings 1927-1964, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Photographs of the Bunch Family n.d., 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Photographs of European and Other Trips n.d. (Box 4)
  - Photographs of the Lewis and Related Families 1935, n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Photographs--Miscellaneous 1920's, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Postcards n.d. (Box 4)
  - Silhouettes of Tilghman Howard Bunch 1935 (Box 4)
  - Statement of Accounts of Tilghman Howard Bunch 1922-1931 (Box 4)
  - Miscellany 1912-1954, n.d.
    Grammar School Diplomas of Laura Crease and Tilghman Bunch; the U.S. Naval Academy B.S. degree of Bunch; certificates commemorating the crossing of the Arctic Circle, the Equator, and the Straits of Magellan; a photograph of Greece; a photograph of the First Annual Banquet of the American Corn Millers Federation; a photograph of a football team; a family photograph; wedding photographs; a photograph of Lt. Bunch and Fred A. Britten; and photographs of the U.S.S. Mayflower